# BRUCE A. FORSEE, PH.D.

12189 Eddystone Ct. • Woodbridge, VA 22192 • bruceforsee@gmail.com • 703-501-1623

# EDUCATOR, PASTOR, TEACHER

Self-motivated with the ability to work independently; yet, fully dedicated to the importance of working in a team. Extensive experience teaching in a lecture format and in the classroom. Ability to work with volunteers as well as paid staff. Proven record of fulfilling long-term commitments and meeting deadlines. Skilled at editing documents for content, clarity, grammar, and punctuation. Passionate and knowledgeable about the nature and message of the Bible. Working knowledge of biblical Greek and Hebrew.

# **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Leadership
- Comprehensive knowledge of the Bible
- Proven speaking and teaching skills
- Excellent communication skills, verbal and written
- Commitment to team-building
- Computer competency with ability to learn new software applications

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Alexandria Presbyterian Church (PCA), Alexandria, Virginia

May 2015 – June 2017

#### DIRECTOR OF ADULT EDUCATION & VISITATION

- Designed, supervised, and maintained Adult Education programs
- Evaluated educational needs of congregation of 500 and developed curriculum to meet those needs
- Interviewed, selected, and coached adult teachers
- Taught weekly adult Sunday School class; preached periodically
- Hosted weekly home Bible Study / Fellowship group.
- Counseled and advised individuals, couples, and families in the church
- Regularly visited and encouraged those unable to attend church services

#### **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Wrote and produced curriculum for several ongoing Sunday evening training classes
- Developed a system for training, scheduling, and organizing adult teachers
- Established a plan of systematic teaching for the adult education program

### Alexandria Bible Church, Alexandria, Virginia

November 1988 - May 2015

#### FULL TIME SENIOR PASTOR

- Senior pastor of a church with 100-member congregation
- Supervised all ministries of the church
- Preached every Sunday morning and taught other classes as needed
- Performed necessary counseling, weddings, funerals
- Organized special events, such as annual mission conferences and church anniversary celebrations
- Organized, staffed, and implemented outreach programs

• Prepared, led, and managed all board meetings

# ACADEMIC TEACHING EXPERIENCE

### **Bob Jones University**

September 1977 – May 1979

### TEACHING ASSISTANT, FRESHMAN ENGLISH

- Prepared, supervised, and taught four weekly classes
- Evaluated student performance, grade compositions and tests
- Recorded grades, documented student work, determined and posted grades

# **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Theology • M.A. in Bible • B.A. in Bible

Bob Jones University • 1700 Wade Hampton Blvd, Greenville, SC 29614

# PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Seminars and conferences of Christian Counseling and Educational Foundation (CCEF) and National Association of Nouthetic Counselors (NANC)
- Intensive counseling training from Biblical Counseling Foundation (BCF)
- Periodic attendance of meetings of the Evangelical Theological Society (ETS)

### COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

- Volunteer chaplain at INOVA Alexandria Hospital for twelve years
- Taught parenting classes at a local home for abused women
- Organized community groups to help seniors clean and repair their homes